McLennan County Office of Price Administration records, Inclusive: 1941-1946, Bulk: 1945
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
McLennan County Office of Price Administration records
Inclusive: 1941-1946, Bulk: 1945
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
4052
McLennan County Office of Price Administration
13 folders.
The McLennan County Office of Price Administration records include various records from Waco area businesses, relating to operations during World War II in Waco, Texas.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
The McLennan County Office of Price Administration was a local office of the national Office of Price Administration. This was a federal government office which attempted to keep prices stable and set maximum price amounts vendors could charge for essential consumer goods during World War II.
Scope and Content
The McLennan County Office of Price Administration includes records on various local businesses serving "malt beverages" and several documents from local resident John Allen, including a war ration book and certificate of transfer for a vehicle.
Arrangement
The McLennan County Office of Price Administration was arranged by business prior to this finding aid. It is unknown if this was the original order of the collection when it came to The Texas Collection.
Currently, the collection is arranged in two series: I. Businesses and II. John Allen.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 4052. Acquired 2018-03-09
Index Terms
Subjects
Business enterprises -- Texas --Waco.; World War, 1939-1945 -- United States.
Genres
Business correspondence.; Ration books.; Records (Documents)
- Businesses, 1945-1946; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains materials on the McLennan County Office of Price Administration's efforts to regulate "malted beverages" at specific businesses in Waco.
  - Casa Blanca Circle Club, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Rendezvous Bar, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Rendezvous Night Club, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ribble Corner Cafe, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Riesel Coffee Shop, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Roosevelt Hotel Coffee Shop, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Royal Bowling Lanes, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Royal Confectionary, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Scottie's Club, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Slavonic Benevolent Order of the State of Texas, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Steve's Cafe, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- John Allen, 1941, undated; 2
  This series contains a war ration book and a certificate of transfer for a vehicle, both issues to a John Allen in Waco.
  - War Ration Book, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Passenger Car, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)